Guide to the New York University Student Organizations Web Collection MC.375
New York University Archives
New York University Student Organizations Web Collection
2013-ongoing
New York University Archives
New York University
MC.375
129 websites in 129 archived websites.
This collection contains websites related to the online presence of student organizations and student activities at New York University, the bulk of which come from 2013-2015.
Arrangement
Arranged into four series:
Series I: Student Blogs
Series II: Student Organization Event Ephemera
Series III: Student Organization News
Series IV: Online Communities
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Facebook is inconsistently captured and plays back. Majority of 2022 Facebook crawls were performed with Webrecorder to resolve capture problems from initial captures.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Websites were initially selected by Aleksandr Gelfand from September 2013-January 2014 through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Appraisal
Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. FourSquare was blocked from capture.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains websites related to student organizations and activities at New York University, the bulk of which come from 2013-2015. Blogs and other websites cover news from around the university and New York City, as well as advice for current and prospective students. Some websites cover events that student organization put together, as well as NYU student organizations in the news. News coverage includes topics such as NYU Greek life, NYU alumni, the Objectivist Club, and LGBTQIA+ community. Events include music and theater performances, club meetings, fundraisers, and conferences. There are many Facebook pages in this collection, modelled off websites and blogs such as Craigslist Missed Connections, Humans of New York, or Overheard in New York but about NYU and its students.
Historical Note
This collection was created by the University Archives in 2013 to collect a sampling of student organization activities in the mid 2010s. The websites in the collection were derived from club lists found at the Office of Student Affairs, yearbooks, and Google search results.
College student newspapers and periodicals.; College students -- New York (N.Y.); Student activities.; Online social networks.
- Series I: Student Blogs, 2013-ongoing
  Arrangement
  Websites are arranged in the order in which they were added to the collection.
  Scope and Contents
  Series consists of blogs documenting the student experience at NYU.
  Accruals
  https://nyulocal.com/ is accrued monthly. https://meet.nyu.edu/ is accrued quarterly.
  - Free and Public Events at NYU, October 2013-July 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    This blog lists many of the free and public events held on and around the NYU campus, including conferences, lectures, book signings, screenings, concerts, and more. Blog dates from 2008-2014.
  - Spring in New York 2013, October 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    The Spring in New York blog is a supplement to the Spring in New York University website and is intended to be the visiting student's preparation guide for coming to NYU for the spring term. Dates from 2012-2013.
  - Meet NYU, December 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Meet NYU is a blog produced by New York University Admissions intended to aid students in the application process by educating them about resources and providing advice. It includes videos and posts on application advice, information on campus resources, city life, communities and clubs, athletics, civic engagement, academics, study abroad, research, faculty, the Washington Square and Downtown Brooklyn campuses.
- Series II: Student Organization Event Ephemera, 2013-2015
  Series consists of event announcements held by NYU's student organizations.
  - Film Remix 2006 Project, September 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    The goal of the NYU remix project is to choose one of the given trilogies and "edit down the footage into a parody of the original, adding or removing elements (voiceovers, scenes, etc) as necessary."
  - NYU Garba, October-November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Mobilize Against Mavi Marmara War Criminal @ NYU Thursday, October-November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - GAPS Welcome Social for HDSI/Ed Psych Students, October-November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Headless Society Fundraiser, October 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Fundraiser staged to raise the means for publish "The Guillotine," the magazine of the Headless Society.
  - SCPS History Club Holds Senior Project Symposium About Punk Rock/Battle of Lepanto, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Alumni Nick Reilly (punk rock) and Vanja Glusica (Battle of Lepanto) presented their research.
  - Cardinal Newman Club General Body Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Poly event at November 16, 2010.
  - SHURUQ 2009, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Bhangra Fall 2013 Tryouts, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Event on September 7, 2013.
  - Black Tie Affair, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Black Family Reunion, Caribbean Students Association, and NAACP @ NYU hosted the 2nd Annual "Night Under the Stars," to benefit The CityKids Foundation on April 14, 2001.
  - World Faith Spring Benefit, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - SEXas Hold'em for NYU UAID, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Students for Justice in Palestine Film Screening: Bil'in Habibti, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Screening on October 21, 2011.
  - Literacy Review Workshops, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    All-day workshop on September 28, 2012. Topics include "Take the Subway: Writing Stories of Our Daily Lives," "English as a Sibling Language," "The Process Approach to Writing," and "Using Music to Facilitate Academic English for Basic Writers."
  - Conversations on Ethics: An Evening of Philosophy and Photography, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Clive Davis Dept. of Recorded Music Presents: the 2010 REMMYS, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Dangerbox: The Last Show Ever, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Marrow for Tomorrow @ Strawberry Fest!, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Meet the Mormons, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU's 25th Annual Strawberry Festival: Japanther and Screaming Females, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Jewish Student Union General Body Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Poly event on November 29, 2010.
  - International Students Organization Presents: Valentine's Day Snackbar, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Poly event on February 13, 2012.
  - Gerontology Student Collective Presents: Careers in Aging Panel Event at New York University, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Gallatin Theatre Troupe's 2nd Annual Musical Theatre Cabaret: Songs You Don't Know (Composers You Do!), November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Event on March 30, 2013.
  - Gallatin Review Reading, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Event on April 30, 2013.
  - NYU Gallatin Cinema Society's Spring 2012 Season, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Re/Forming Identities: The Artist's Voice, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Four day conference in February 2013.
  - Construction Managers Association of America General Body Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Poly event on September 13, 2012
  - CBS and NYU Stern Asian Business Club Annual Fall All-School Party, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Animal Assisted Therapy in Social Work Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Silver School event on September 9, 2013.
  - SoulAviv Concert at NYU, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Koach, Kesher, and Shalhevet Shabbat, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Making Space for the Arts: Reflections on the Center for an Urban Future's 2010 Report Time to Be Creative, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Panel on sustaining creativity on February 25, 2011.
  - Objectivist Club at NYU, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Events for the Objectivist Club for 2009-2010. The club promots the philosophy of Ayn Rand.
  - TASS Night Market at NYU, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Taiwanese American Student Society event on April 11, 2013.
  - Last Fall T-Party Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Norwegian Wood Screening with Corners of Culture, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Corners of Culture International Potluck, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - CosCafe 2013 presented by NYU Club Anime, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU for Japan: First Annual NYU Club Anime Cos-Cafe, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU's Child[Not]Soldier: Fundraiser, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - World Vision & C(n)s: Charity Banquet 2012, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Shy Girl Social, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Kurt Pellegrino Jiu Jitsu Seminar, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Amnesty International @ NYU: Jamnesty Benefit Concert, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - 2020 Vision: The Fulture is Yours! Conference, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Conference presented by 85 Broads & NYU Stern on April 24, 2010.
  - Tech@NYU, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Events for Tech@NYU in Fall 2011.
  - The Collective Presents Celebrate Our Voices, An Open Arts Night, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Event on December 2, 2011.
  - nyu2008: Zeta Sigma Phi Recruitment 2005, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Cleftomaniacs Album Fundraiser, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Team Agent during NYU Asian Heritage Month: Bone Marrow Drives to Save Lives, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - AHM@NYU Opening Ceremony with Wong Fu Productions, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - An Evening with Somaly Mam (ACT and Project Futures), November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - "Not My Life" Film Screening and Panel Discussion, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Nowroz 1390! with Farhad Darya, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - DJ Culture Club Movie Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Disability Studies and Disabilities Community at NYU Interest Meeting, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Spring 2013 NYU Community Chess Tournament, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Bella Quisqueya, November 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
  - ASL Club at NYU First Meeting, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Indecision 2012: Hillel NYU Elections, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Intercollegiate Swing Exchange 2013, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Student Producers Association One-on-One Troubleshooting, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Ski and Snowboard Club Killington, Vermont Trip, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Ski and Snowboard Club Mont Tremblant, Canada Trip, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU SSA Elections, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Norooz Celebration, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Violet Lights Party, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Korean Graduate Students Association Violet Lights Party on April 12, 2012.
  - Think Coffee Keep a Child Alive at NYU Event, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Modeling Tryouts for IJC's 4th Annual Fashion Show, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Iranian Jewish Club of NYU presents 30 Years After Civic Action Conference, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - IFA@NYU presents Mr. Philippines 2010, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Founders Forum, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Pitch event presented by the Entrepreneurship & Innovation Association on November 7, 2013.
  - Encounter Large Group, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Encounter Christian Fellowship event.
  - Currently Speaking Event, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Economics Club event on March 8, 2013.
  - Fall Meetup, February 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Economics Club event on October 19, 2012.
  - Wood: The Musical, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Students for the Collaborative Arts musical for 2007.
  - 194 Recordings to Showcase 6 Artists from NYU's Clive David Dept of Recorded Music at the CMJ Music Festival, Oct 24, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article from October 16, 2008.
  - 194 Recordings Rubber Tracks Showcase, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Variety night of NYU neosoul, hip-hop, indie folk, and pop-rock bands on November 26, 2013.
  - African Heritage Month Fashion Show, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Images from the fashion show.
  - NYU's Chapter of ASDA, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - New York Armenian Students' Association and the NYU Armenian Club Present Book Reading and Signing with Writer/Translator Christopher Atamian, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Event on March 8, 2013.
  - NYU's BSU x NYU Poly's NSBE Present: The Black Family Reunion, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Annual Dharma Zen Lecture at NYU Buddhism Club, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Earth Week 2011, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Radhanath Swami Speaking Engagement, May 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    Speaking engagement for the Krsna-Bhakti Club at New York University (NYU) on November 8, 2010.
  - NYU's Big Fat Greek Takeover, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Relief for Greece fundraiser presented by the Greek Dance Troupe at NYU and the Hellenic Heritage Association on April 6, 2014.
  - Project (Persian) Runway, December 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on the Jewish Week on November 28, 2008 by Amy Spiro.
- Series III: Student Organization News, 2013-2015
  Series consists of news stories relating to NYU's student organizations and their activities. The series represents a sampling of news from 2013-2015.
  - CCC [Chinese Cultural Club] starts online petition to stop Falun Gong in NYU, October 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on FACTS on August 13, 2007.
  - Censors Win at NYU, October 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on FIRE (Foundation for Individual Rights in Education) on March 30, 2006 by Charles Mitchell.
  - NYU Suppresses Objectivist Club's Free Speech, October 2013 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on the Artlasphere on March 29, 2006.
  - Bill de Blasio's student activist at New York University work prepared him for the world of city politics, June 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on the Daily News by Greg B. Smith on October 6, 2013.
  - No Closets in This NYU Frat House, June 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on the New York Post on March 27, 2007 by David Andreatta.
  - Gay Brotherhood: Antithesis of the 'Animal House' Drunken Excesses, June 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on ABC News written on March 29, 2007 by Susan Donaldson James.
  - We had a sorority girl rank all of NYU's fraternities (sorry DKE), June 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on Thrillist written on October 5, 2014.
  - NYU's Queer Union Protests Own Blood Drive, June 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    Article on Gothamist written on February 26, 2011 by Jaya Saxena.